<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <atom:link href="https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 17:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jboss_experience</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2018/jboss_experience</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2018/jboss_experience</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;layout: post
 title: “Share my experience with JBoss developer community”
 description:
 headline:
 modified: 2018-01-01
 category: personal
 tags: []
 feature-img:
 mathjax:
 chart:
 author: ‘Aniol Vicens Lloret’
 comments: true
 featured: false&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;share-my-experience-with-jboss-developer-community&quot;&gt;Share my experience with JBoss developer community.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;experience-with-jboss-developer-community-and-with-open-source-projects&quot;&gt;Experience with JBoss developer community and with Open Source Projects.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, my name is Aniol, I am a 13-year-old student, and I am participating in the Google Code-In contest. I’m here to talk about my JBoss developer community experience that I have lived since Google Code-in started. JBoss was not one of my main goals to work on. But in the end, I chose it because of the variety of projects that there were and the different amount of tasks that there were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mentors--students&quot;&gt;Mentors &amp;amp; Students&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In when the mentors, moments are very nice and friendly. Now as for the community (the developers), I have not had too much contact with them but I have spoken with someone through the chat and they seem very kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-source-projects&quot;&gt;Open Source Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participating in open source projects is very fun if you like to program, a good open source project is Google Code-in, a very fun open source project with prizes that you can easily earn if you are consistent and commit to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This in addition to helping to make known your skills will help you develop your creativity and make more people known.
You do not necessarily have to contribute programing, you can also do something by contributing ideas or modifying documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jboss-community-and-open-source-projects&quot;&gt;JBoss Community and Open Source Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t have previous experience in a real open source project, and with JBoss Community I started with those, JBoss Community made me release that is the quality what matters not the quantity. I have made a great advance since I started, and that has taken me effort that I never thought I should give to program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;try-hard-and-you-will-see-what-you-get&quot;&gt;Try hard and you will see what you get!&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gci_experience_blog</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2018/gci_experience_blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2018/gci_experience_blog</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;layout: post
 title: “Swastik’s GCI Experience”
 description:
 headline:
 modified: 2018-01-01
 category: personal
 tags: []
 feature-img:
 mathjax:
 chart:
 author: ‘Swastik Das’
 comments: true
 featured: false&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##GOOGLE CODE IN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google code-in is a world-wide competition held by the folks at Google annually which provides a platform for us to explore new and interesting organizations and also help them! With tasks in all branches of cyber-computing such as: Code, User Interface, Documentation/Training, Quality Assurance and Outreach/Research it is the ultimate competition. It mainly aims at open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##My Google Code In Experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Swastik Das, a  student of class XI at SAI International School, Bhubaneswar, India.
I heard about Google Code In from Sampriti Panda who has participated in GCI trice earlier and has also been the Grand prize Winner last year.
From childhood computer have fascinated me. I love everything related to them let it be gaming, editing stuffs or coding.
This year I decided to participate in the GCI.
I chose JBoss Community on reading that it is related to Java.
I got to learn about many open-source softwares. They are great to work with. You can use them and also modify and upgrade those softwares which is a great thing.
I learnt how to develop apps, integrate authentication methods, designing webpages and various other stuffs.
At present I know Java, Javascript, C++, C#, Swift, HTML, CSS and I would love to learn more and master in these programming languages too.
Before GCI, I had very less knowledge about opensource. I wasn’t aware of the tremendous benefits it gives. But now I love using opensource softwares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Mentors
The mentors are really good and cooperative.
They check all our works and also advice us on improving our programming skills and also to rectify to mistakes.
They are really friendly and never step back in clearing doubts or helping in any other ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#What I have gained till now from GCI&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A t-shirt(After completion of 3 tasks)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A whole lot of knowledge in the field of web page designing and app development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also got to know about many open source softwares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##End
In the end I would conclude this by saying that GCI gave me a nice opportunity to improve my coding skills as well as learn many new things. It also gave me new friends and supporting mentors who ere always there to guide us. Whether I get prize or not, I ll forever remember such valuable experience because learning is more important than winning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank You&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>MY GOOGLE CODE-IN EXPERIENCE</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/MY-GOOGLE-CODE-IN-EXPERIENCE</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/MY-GOOGLE-CODE-IN-EXPERIENCE</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-google-code-in-experience&quot;&gt;MY GOOGLE CODE-IN EXPERIENCE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google code-in is a world-wide competition held by the folks at Google annually which provides a platform for us to explore new and interesting organisations and also help them! With tasks in all branches of cyber-computing such as: Code, User Interface, Documentation/Training, Quality Assurance and Outreach/Research it is the ultimate competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found about GCI from a friend a year ago but I was too late to join in the fun. Now that I know how epic Google Code-in is, I really regret not being able to participate last year. Nevertheless, this year I have planned to complete as many GCI tasks as I can and not waste this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mentors are a great addition to the competition. Without them, I probably wouldn’t have any successful submissions. They really do help a lot and narrow the tasks down for us to understand it. No matter how wrong the first draft is or even the tenth draft. They keep on providing their services relentlessly. Their motivational chat-bits also keep us focus and regulate the ginormous enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about GCI is that it motivates us to surf the internet and learn to do things previously unheard-of. For example; Forking a Project in GitHub. It was something which I at first hearing about, thought of food but later I understood what it really was and how relevant it is. Never would this be possible had GCI not existed. The JBoss community can help me in this completion by introducing more tasks for me to accomplish so that I reach their leaderboard. It would be a great honour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task is where the fear lies. After that it becomes your passion as it did for me. I remember my peers bragging about the number of tasks they completed last year and truthfully I was overwhelmed. How could a child of my age complete so many tasks in a world renowned completion I asked myself but now as I am a part of GCI just as much as they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to constantly switch tabs between the problem, the procedure and help tabs that the google search engine helpfully provided me. Trying to piece together the solution and deciphering the answer to every problem really makes you feel alive. One after the other, slowly but surely each sub-problem I knocked out of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I completed my first task, I was hocked on to it like an anchor. I was the best experience by far. I had actually accomplished something and in doing so also benefited an actual organisation. That feeling is like no other. Soon I started to hunt for a second and a third. The third meant that I would get a google t-shirt from as a prize. I was psyched! I must admit I wasn’t the fastest to reach so far but I was defiantly determined and disciplined for the task. Day and night, I emptied the internet, disburdening it of its information and piecing together information to finish the task. ASAP!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Google Code-in Experience</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/yashtyagiblog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/yashtyagiblog</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;experience-with-the-google-code-in&quot;&gt;EXPERIENCE WITH THE GOOGLE CODE-IN:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How I got to know about Google Code-In-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a technocrat, I have a strong passion for coding, designing and developing. But I didn’t found the right platform to work. But one day I heard about Google Code-In from one of my friend. I gathered information about it from my friends and internet and later decided to participate in the contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The day when Google Code-In started-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First day was quite exciting. As it was my first time, I decided to go with a simple task. The level of the task is quite variant so that everyone can participate and solve based on their skills. First day it took me a little time to search through the list of all organisation and decide one. Finally, I decided to go with Jboss community for their logo designing task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I choose Jboss Community-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the very first day, Jboss community emerges to be the best organisation. I scroll through its tasks and found quite a few that were matching my domain and interest. Although, here competition is quite high but still I preferred to go with it. Also, mentors are very supportive and have helped me in guiding through various problems where I got stuck. Tasks are reviewed in few hours as comparison to the other organisations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I hope to learn in this program-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that being a participant in this international level program will not only enhance my skills but will also boost up my confidence. As I have never been a part of such contests, so I have learnt many new things including how one should approach a mentor, discuss problems with them and how to work on GitHub. I got to learn many cool stuff like creating CSS animation, logos, working with Java script and many more. I hope I’ll make it to leaderboard this year and contribute my best to open-source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Google Code-in Experience</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/aiyaad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/aiyaad</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Google Code-In is a program that is aimed at encouraging middle-school and high-school students to participate in Open Source. It usually runs for 7-8 weeks during Northern Hemisphere winters. The tasks given in Google Code-In are tasks that would take an experienced well-versed developer 2-3 hours to do so that a student would be able to do it within 5 days. You can apply via Google Melange portal. The applications for Google Code-In are open now. You can choose the organizations, apply for a task and the mentor of a task will choose from the pool of task applicants. If you are a within 13-17 years old and still in school, please apply for Code-In. I had a great experience being a participant there. People are extremely helpful and you will learn a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I registered myself in Google Code-In contest and soon started reading about the organization
and out of so many organizations I like JBoss Community. I love designing things like logos, UI/UX, and a little bit of code. I started with the designing tasks and completed them soon and moved to the coding part where I build a basic iOS app. So far its been a wonderful experience in learning so many things like interacting with mentors and the hurdles you have to cross to complete the tasks,
whenever these hurdles come you experience something new and this experience is kind of a new learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to know about Open-Source a year before when my brother started working on different open source on Github, I liked what he did and coding kind of attracted me, it looked cool but being an open source developer gives you a lot of experience about a lot of platforms at the same time, I liked the way my brother could pick any project of his own choice to work on. He liked python and knew it. So, he did most of his projects related to python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I guess my open source journey started with this and when I heard about Google Code-In contest, it kind of boosted my energy and I thought I should enter this contest and so I did, and till now it’s going well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I gave up very easily, I always thought that the tasks were too difficult or I didn’t understand coding and I was too shy to ask for help on IRC while other students asked about more complex stuff, I thought people will laugh at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second time, I began doing the task and with the grand prize in my mind, I got rid of my shyness, so I began and tried to always be working on a task It was frustrating sometimes but I kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was doing great, Now I target an average of at least one task per day, and I am going with it. Tasks are a little bit difficult but I don’t start with them before I learn the language or design or whatever the task is about, I go through it first and then start working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till now my Google Code-In experience has been going good and I look for learning more things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Code-In has been a change in my life as I am looking for tasks and eventually new things to learn and so far I am learning and experiencing new things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank You, Google. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Code In 2017: My Experience with the &quot;Extended Hackathon&quot;</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/Bolt108post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/Bolt108post</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-experience-at-google-code-in-2017&quot;&gt;My Experience at Google Code In 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my second and I suppose the last year that I will be able to do Google Code In (I’ll be too old next year :( ). A lot has changed since the first time I participated in Google Code In, which was in 2016. During the 2016 competition I didn’t have much experience with Git or Github so I was struggling to complete many tasks. I ended up completing three tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then I have used Git and Github a lot more and feel much more comfortable using them. This year I changed my strategy to work harder, put in more effort and figure things out as I go. The key is to stick on one task and only one task until you complete it. This time around I am finding Google Code In much more engaging and interesting thanks in part to the great tasks by JBoss community but also because I am motivated and compelled to complete as many tasks I can whilst maintaining a high quality for each task due to this being my last opportunity to participate. I find myself working on GCI during any free moment in my day. The satisfaction of having a task accepted is immense, and every time a task is accepted I feel like I am one step closer to my goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like Google Code In because I see it as an extended hackathon. I’ve been to hackathons in the past and they have all compelled and somewhat forced me to learn something new in order to build a prototype in time. In the same way GCI motivates me to learn new things in order to complete tasks and therefore improve my skills to take on more challenging tasks. I feel that the JBoss community tasks are perfect for me as they challenge me in the right way. Thats why all the tasks I have completed and intend to complete are from JBoss Community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-have-learned-so-far-at-gci-2017&quot;&gt;What I have learned so far at GCI 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating pull requests and issues&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working with various new technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting involved with the community i.e. helping others and receiving help.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to setup a local server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What MongoDB is and how it is installed on Ubuntu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The basics of using Xcode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to continue to learn new things through completing GCI tasks so that I can develop my skills further!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Year at GCI</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/My-Year-at-GCI</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/My-Year-at-GCI</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This will be my first year participating in Google Code-In.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like many other students, I am extremely excited to work on open-source tasks for various organizations. Having been a part of several open-source activities previously, I’ve learnt plenty from my past experiences. I believe that Google Code-In will be no exception.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward several weeks and over a dozen tasks, I’m glad to have taken part in this competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I originally expected to bolster my knowledge and skills in various languages and fields of software development. What I have learnt has gone beyond my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Code-In has provided me with the platform to meet students all over the world and have a stake in various wonderful organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been my first, and unfortunately my last year participating in Google Code-In. I’m really grateful to the organization JBoss for their efforts and patience (this is their first year in GCI!), my fellow students who have been really friendly and Google for giving all of us this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Google Code-in Experience with JBoss Community</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/jatin-luthra</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/jatin-luthra</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;strong&gt;Jatin Luthra&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;Passionate Coder&lt;/strong&gt; from India. This is my Third GCI. Few years back, I attended a seminar in my school which was conducted by a Google Employee from the school’s Alumni.
Upset from last GCI, I made a knot that &lt;strong&gt;Quality » Quantity&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the reason that I stopped counting my tasks and started looking forward to What I am submitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difficulties&quot;&gt;Difficulties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only difficulty I faced is that It is my Class 12 which means my final Board class. So balancing was difficult but I am trying to give my 100% to both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I generally do &lt;strong&gt;Coding&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt; tasks. The main reason is that I can contribute to community and help others too by documenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;things-acheived&quot;&gt;Things Acheived&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More Experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attention and help from the Mentors (A Lot!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helping others as I go on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improvement in my Coding with the help of Mentors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motivation and Appreciation from all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Hope that I can provide my best to this &lt;strong&gt;JBoss community&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Open Source World&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Google Code-in experience with JBoss</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/gcitask-sid</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/gcitask-sid</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first GCI. I’m a teen from India who is a &lt;strong&gt;Graphics Designer&lt;/strong&gt;. I got to know about this competition from my schoolmates. It’s been about 10 days and I’ve completed around 10 tasks. I’d a pretty slow start but then I caught up my pace. The real difficulty with this competition is that it’s around the time of my examinations. It’s a quite tough task to do both GCI &amp;amp; exams and sometimes the time &lt;strong&gt;“equilibrium”&lt;/strong&gt; for both is not maintained. My biggest fear in this event is to abandon a task and feel gloomy about it. Right now I’m completing all the &lt;strong&gt;“User interface”&lt;/strong&gt; tasks and some basic coding tasks as well. The overall spirit amongst us is high and I hope I get the chance to achieve something huge in my life !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-have-i-gained-&quot;&gt;What have I gained ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The GCI t-shirt (jk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experience about professionalism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The experience of meeting fellow participants around the globe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mentorship given by our great mentors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The chance to see where I stand amongst others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope my contributions to &lt;strong&gt;Open Source&lt;/strong&gt; would help this community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Code-In Is Awesome</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/anhai-wang</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/anhai-wang</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a week since I participated in Google Code-In as a 11th-grade, and I have to say that &lt;strong&gt;THIS IS AWESOME&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encountered coding at about 7th grade and was highly impressed by the amaze of making dead things alive with simple instructions. Til now I’ve made some little progress on a handful small projects built for myself, yet contributing to the open source world and collaborating with other devs is something I never did before until I get to know GCI by a lucky chance, and that is full of fun and &lt;strong&gt;EXCITEMENT&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a great time working with JBoss Community which is actually the most popular org in GCI currently XD. Competing with other passionate contestants while working with them at the same time is really challenging yet fascinating. Even though there’re some technologies I’m not good at or haven’t encountered before, contributing to the construction of those project with what I know and what I’m capable of gives me unprecedented satisfactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wish I have a good time seeing billions of my tasks got approved XD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Google Code-In Experience</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/sachinrammoorthyblog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/sachinrammoorthyblog</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been more than an hour and I haven’t moved an inch. My brother has made several attempts to try to get me to look at him, but I don’t budge. This is time for concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what happens to me when I am engrossed in any task. And Google Code In has done just that. It has only been about 2 days since it started, but ever since then, every spare moment I have had the privilege of experiencing is spent browsing the GCI Home page for new tasks or hoping for approval on my current tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find programming to be a fascinating subject, and want to pursue a career in this field. I am absolutely certain that Google Code In and JBoss, the organisation that the majority of my tasks belong to, will help me make this dream a reality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My GCI Experience</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/blog-post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/blog-post</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-experience-at-google-code-in-2017&quot;&gt;My Experience at Google Code In 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of competitive programming had been relatively new to me until I heard of Google Code In and Code Jam. I decided to have a go at 2017’s Code In, expecting a new and fun-filled experience. And I sure wasn’t disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was waiting for the opening of registrations on November 28, refreshing the page every five seconds to check if the contest had begun yet. And finally, three minutes past the scheduled time, I was able to register. The tasks page had an unending number of challenging tasks, and I was tempted to claim each and every one of them. Being a first time participant, I didn’t know that only one task could be claimed at a time. The task I chose first was a UI design one, as UI development and coding were among my favourite categories. Unfortunately, I couldn’t complete the task, and had to abandon it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I continued checking out other tasks, and claimed a logo design task by JBoss Community. It got approved, and that was a major boost in my confidence. Since then, I have claimed many UI/coding tasks, and I have been enjoying completing all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-gained-at-gci-2017&quot;&gt;What I gained at GCI 2017&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I could acquire a very specific skill set required to complete tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meeting people around the world was a delight, as I could learn a lot of things from them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mentors were helpful, and were more like peers who would patiently talk to us and help solve our issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, GCI was a sweet and extravagant event for me, and it has been more of a learning experience than a competiton, and has helped me witness the true power of open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m surely participating every year from now on!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Saba's GCI Experience</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/SabaKhukhunashvili</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/SabaKhukhunashvili</guid>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-google-code-in&quot;&gt;{What is Google Code-In}&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Code-in is a contest to introduce pre-university students (ages 13-17) to open source software development.
Open source organizations (chosen by Google) provide students with a list of tasks for which pupils work for 7 weeks.All organizations have the mentors who are assisting in the task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;types-of-tasks&quot;&gt;{Types of tasks}&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tasks are categorized as: Code, Documentation/Training, Outreach/Research, Quality Assurance and User Interface. Students can claim and work on the task that interests them. They are provided anything between 3 to 7 days for its completion. Once the student feels their work is ready, they submit their work for review through the contest website. Mentors from the organization evaluate the work, provide feedback, and if it’s complete, approve it! Otherwise, specific important feedback is provided, and the student updates the work. Once a task is accepted, the student can claim another!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prizes&quot;&gt;{Prizes}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as a Google contest without Prizes, Google Code-In is not exception too. 
You get an assured digital certificate, if you complete 1 task you can even earn a google tshirt if you complete 3 tasks. :D 
At the end of the contest, five finalists are chosen to get hoodies and two of them are chosen to be the grand prize winners and earn themselves a trip to Google Headquarters in Mountain View, California!
The more tasks you do, with creativity and quality, the better chance you have to win the mega prize&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-take-part-in-it&quot;&gt;{Why you should take part in it?}&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google code in aims to inculcate values of teamwork in the students. You even get a chance to, make friends from different countries around the world and most importantly get great experience. Prizes are definitely Google’s way to thank you for your hardwork. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-my-google-code-in-experience-&quot;&gt;{ My Google Code-In Experience }&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three weeks have passed since the start of Google’s event. as for the organization I chose the Jboss  Community by Redhat, because I was  familiar with the technologies and programming languages that were required to be a part of it. As of now, most of my  tasks are related to Android. Daily group work with foreigners has given me great experience in communication, writing clean code &amp;amp; version control.The mentors and even the participating students are very helpful, I have learned a lot from them.
During this time, we have created an Android Library, several applications and sites.  Two weeks after the start of the event, when I saw my organization’s page, I found a list of leaders where my name was written, this motivated me to do more and more stuff and cause my parents to be proud of me. :) I want to win and I will do everything for it but the competition is huge and even if I don’t win, I’ll be happy in being a part of the leader list. I. made a great decision by joining Google Code-In and i advise you to participate in Google Code-In and try your fate between 6500 pupils. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saba Khukhunashvili&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Contributing to Open Source</title>
        <link>https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/contributing-to-open-source</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jboss-outreach.github.io/blog/2017/contributing-to-open-source</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Contributing to open source can be exciting as well as scary at the same time. If you are a newbie, then entering into the world of open source can be a really overwhelming experience for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;“open source”&lt;/strong&gt; refers to something people can modify and share because its design is publicly accessible. Open source software is software developed by and for the user community. If you want to contribute to open source projects then &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; is the next thing you need to be familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/lakhina/blog.jboss-outreach.org/blob/addPost/img/open-source-contribution-model.jpg?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Contribution model&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For contributing to open source, you don’t need to be a developer. A non-programmer can also do a variety of stuffs like documentation , designing and suggesting features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation plays a vital role in understanding of the project. Every project repository in GitHub comes with a &lt;strong&gt;README&lt;/strong&gt; file stating how to use the project and how to set up the environment for running it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-contribute-to-open-source&quot;&gt;How to contribute to open source?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a project meeting your requirement and skill set.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pick an issue to work upon or raise an issue if you find some bug in the project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After fixing the problem highlighted in the issue, open a pull request for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If your pull request need to be worked on further, then it’s  better to write &lt;em&gt;WIP&lt;/em&gt; [work in progress]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try following the guidelines while submitting a patch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;easy-isnt-it&quot;&gt;Easy! Isn’t it?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After following these  little steps, you can congratulate yourself. You have now contributed to open source which felt terrifying in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an amazing experience to get to know that a project you worked on is now being used by millions of users. Moreover, you get a chance to interact with other people of your domain. You can learn from them and improve to an extend you have not anticipated. &lt;em&gt;So get , set and start contributing!!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
